[Evans] There are many other ways to define find_element.
定义 find_element 还有很多其他方式
I'm going to show you 1 way that takes advantage of another built-in list operation
下面我将展示一种方式 这种方式利用另一个内部的列表操作
that we haven't introduced yet but that makes it much easier to write find_element.
我们尚未介绍这个操作 但是这大大简化了 find_element 的编写
The operation is called index.
这个操作叫做 index (索引)
The index method is invoked on a list.
index 方法在列表上被调用
You pass in a value, and the output in index is the position that that value exists in the list.
你传入一个值 index 的输出是那个值存在于列表中的位置
So the built-in index almost solves find_element exactly the way we want.
所以这个内建 index 几乎完全按照我们的心意解决了 find_element
The difference is when we invoke index on a list that doesn't contain the value we pass in.
不同之处在于 当我们在列表上调用 index 而该列表不包含我们传入的值
Index doesn't return -1. What it does is gives us an error.
index 不会返回 -1 而是显示 error (出错)
So let's look at what happens in the Python interpreter.
我们来看看 Python 解释器中的情况
I'll define a variable p and give it the value of the list 0, 1, 2.
我将定义一个变量 p 并传入列表0 1 2的值
If we invoke index on p, passing in 2, we get as the result 2,
如果我们调用 p.index() 传入2 我们得到的结果是2
which is the position in p where the value 2 occurs.
也就是2这个值在 p 中的位置
For the second example we'll add more 2s in the list,
第二个例子中 我们多加两个2到列表中
and we see that it always gives us the first one.
我们看到 它总是显示第一个2
So the result returned by p index is the first place in the list where that occurs.
所以 p.index 返回的结果是找到值2的第一个位置
Now we'll try an element that doesn't exist in the list.
现在我们将试着传入一个列表中不存在的元素
What we see is instead of getting -1 as a result we get an error
我们看到 结果不是 -1 而是显示出错
that the target element that we looked for doesn't appear in the list.
我们要找的目标元素在列表中不存在
So if we want find_element to have the behavior that's described,
所以 如果我们想让 find_element 完全按照要求行事
we can't quite do it using index directly.
我们就不能直接使用 index
There are some other list operations that might be very helpful, though.
但还有其他一些可能很有帮助的列表操作
So to summarize the behavior of the index method,
总结一下 index 方法的功能
if the value passed in is in the list, it returns the first position where the value is found.
如果传入的值存在于列表中 过程返回找到这个值的第一个位置
This is exactly what we wanted for find_element.
这正是我们想让 find_element 做的
The problem is if the value is not found in the list, it produces an error.
问题在于 如果这个值在列表中找不到 过程就会显示出错
There's another list operation that will be useful to allow us to use index to find_element,
还有一个列表操作可以帮助我们使用 index 来编写 find_element
and it's useful for many other things, and that's the in word.
这种方法也对其他很多事情有帮助 那就是单词 in
We've already seen in being used in the for-loop.
我们已经见过 in 被使用在 for 循环中
Here we use the same word in, but in this context it means something different.
这里 我们使用同一个词 in 但是在这个语境下 它的意义有所不同
The syntax is to have a value to the left of the in word followed by the list.
这个句法是在 in 的左边放一个值 in 后面跟一个列表
The syntax is a bit strange compared to the other things we've seen in Python.
这个句法与我们之前见到的 Python 语言相比有些奇怪
It doesn't look like a procedure call, but it's very natural in terms of how it corresponds
它看起来不像一个方法调用 但是 在用英文对这个内容进行表达时
to how we would say this in English.
用它是非常自然的
If we say something like, "Is 3 in the list?"
如果我们说：3在列表中吗？
we would write that in Python as 3 in p.
我们用 Python 语言写出来就是3 in p
So let's see how that works in the interpreter.
我们看看解释器中的情况
Now I'm printing the result of 3 in p.
现在我打印出3 in p 的结果
3 is not in the list, so it prints out False.
3不在列表中 所以打印出来的为假
If I change this to print the result of 2 in p,
如果我把它改成2 in p
we get the value True.
我们得到的值为真
So to summarize the behavior of the in operator,
总结一下 in 操作的功能
if the value is in the list, the output is true.
如果值存在于列表中 输出为真
Otherwise the output is false.
反之为假
Similarly, we can use not in.
类似地 我们可以使用 not in
Not in has the opposite meaning of in.
not in 正好与 in 相反
If the value is not in the list, the result of value not in list is true.
如果值不存在于列表中 那么 not in 列表结果的值为真
If the value is in the list, then the result of value not in list is false.
如果这个值存在于列表中 那么 not in 列表结果的值为假
The value not in list is exactly equivalent to saying not value in list.
〈value〉not in〈list〉完全等同于 not〈value〉in〈list〉
The only reason to have the not in is it's more natural to read it this way in English
采用 not in 的唯一原因是 在英文中 这比把 not 放在值和 in 之间
than having the not between the value and the in.
读起来更顺一些
So now to check that you understand index and in and not in operations,
现在检查一些你是否理解了 index、in 和 not in 等操作
I want you to try to define the find_element procedure again.
我想让你试着再次定义 find_element 函数
It should have the same exact behavior as the ones we've defined before.
它跟我们之前的定义功能一模一样
It should give us the position of the element we're searching for if it exists,
它会给出我们搜索的元素位置 如果该元素存在
and it should give us -1 if it doesn't exist.
如果不存在 它会显示 -1
But this time instead of using a while loop or a for-loop to define it
但是这次 不用 while 循环或 for 循环
see if you can define it using index.
你试试看是否能够使用 index 来定义它